Guide to the Frederic Dannay Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Frederic Dannay Papers,
ca.1920-1982.
Dannay, Frederic, 1905-1982.
85 linear ft (ca.25,000 items in 190 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079731
Biographical Note
Mystery writer, editor, critic of crime fiction, and coauthor with Manfred B. Lee of the Ellery Queen mystery novels and stories.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, outlines and drafts, manuscripts, letters of agreement, contracts, photographs, artwork, and memorabilia. The collection is divided into two parts: the Frederic Dannay Papers and the files of Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine (EQMM). The Dannay papers consist of extensive correspondence with most of the notable mystery writers of this century, as well as well-known authors who sometimes wrote in that genre: Isaac Asimov; Lawrence Block; Ray Bradbury; Perl S Buck; Edgar Rice Burroughs; James M. Cain; Raymond Chandler; Agatha Christie, etc. Most of the novels and short stories written by Dannay and Lee are represented in manuscript form: "The Roman Hat Mystery;" "Ten Day's Wonder;" "Cat of Many Tails;" "The Scarlet Letters;" "The Glass Village;" "The Player on the Other Side;" "And on the Eighth Day," etc. In addition, there are the manuscripts of books edited by Ellery Queen; manuscripts by Ellery Queen Jr.; scripts by Ellery Queen; poetry by Dannay; contracts between Dannay and Lee, as well as between them both as Ellery Queen and numerous parties. There are also manuscripts by such notables as Jorge Luis Borges; Erskine Caldwell; Raymond Chandler; Agatha Christie; Stanley Ellin; William Faulkner; Dashiell Hammett; O Henry; Nigel Morland; Georges Simenon; Muriel Spark; Julian Symons; Roy Vickers; and Cornell Woolrich.
The second part of this collection is the files of Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine (EQMM). Containing some 4,600 manuscripts submitted to the magazine over a period of 40 years, it is an unrivaled collection of its kind. Nearly all of the manuscripts have Dannay's msnuscript corrections.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series:
Series I: Cataloged Series
Series II: Arranged Series
Series III: Documents
Series IV: Artwork and Photographs
Series V: Printed Materials
Series VI: Objects and Memorabilia
Series VII: Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
Series VIII: Arranged manuscripts
Subjects
Allingham, Margery, 1904-1966.; Ambler, Eric, 1909-1998.; Armstrong, Charlotte, 1905-1969.; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992.; Audemars, Pierre.; Avallone, Michael.; Babb, Sanora.; Barzun, Jacques, 1907-; Baxt, George.; Bell, Josephine, 1897-1987.; Bellak, Leopold, 1916-; Bentley, E. C. (Edmund Clerihew), 1875-1956.; Bentley, Eric, 1916-; Bentley, Phyllis Eleanor, 1894-1977.; Berkeley, Anthony, 1893-1971.; Blochman, Lawrence Goldtree, 1900-; Bloch, Lawrence W.; Block, Lawrence.; Bolitho, Hector, 1897-1974.; Boucher, Anthony, 1911-1968.; Borges, Jorge Luis, 1899-1986.; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-; Brand, Christianna, 1907-1988.; Breen, Jon L., 1943-; Brentano, Lowell, 1895-1950.; Britain, William.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Burgess, Gelett, 1866-1951.; Burnett, W. R. (William Riley), 1899-1982.; Burroughs, Edgar Rice, 1875-1950.; Byrne, M. St. Clare (Muriel St. Clare), 1895-; Cain, James M. (James Mallahan), 1892-1977.; Caldwell, Erskine, 1903-1987.; Caldwell, Taylor, 1900-1985.; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961.; Canning, Victor.; Čapek, Karel, 1890-1938.; Carr, Albert H. Z.; Carr, John Dickson, 1906-1977.; Cary, Joyce, 1888-1957.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971.; Chandler, Raymond, 1888-1959.; Charteris, Leslie, 1907-1993.; Chaucer, Geoffrey, d. 1400.; Chekhov, Anton Pavlovich, 1860-1904.; Chesterton, G. K. (Gilbert Keith), 1874-1936.; Christie, Agatha, 1890-1976.; Ciardi, John, 1916-1986.; Clarke, Arthur C. (Arthur Charles), 1917-2008.; Clemens, Cyril, 1902-; Cohn, Roy N.; Costain, Thomas B. (Thomas Bertram), 1885-1965.; Coxe, George Harmon, 1901-; Creasey, John.; Crispin, Edmund, 1921-1978.; Crofts, Freeman Wills, 1879-1957.; Cronin, A. J. (Archibald Joseph), 1896-1981.; Cushing, Richard, 1895-1970.; Daly, Elizabeth, b. 1878.; Damore, Leo.; Davis, Dorothy Salisbury.; Day Lewis, C. (Cecil), 1904-1972.; De Ford, Miriam Allen, 1888-1975.; De La Torre, Lillian, 1902-; Derleth, August William, 1909-1971.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870.; Dickens, Monica, 1915-1992.; Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir, 1859-1930.; Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870.; Du Maurier, Daphne, 1907-1989.; Dunham, Katherine.; Dunsany, Edward John Moreton Drax Plunkett, Baron, 1878-1957.; Eberhart, Mignon Good, 1899-1996.; Ellin, Stanley.; Faulkner, William, 1897-1962.; Ferrars, Elizabeth.; Finney, Jack.; Fish, R. L. (Robert L.); Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Fisher, M. F. K. (Mary Frances Kennedy), 1908-1992.; Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940.; Francis, Dick.; Freeling, Nicolas.; Freeman, R. Austin (Richard Austin), 1862-1943.; Fremlin, Celia.; Gardner, Erle Stanley, 1889-1970.; Garfield, Brian, 1939-; Garve, Andrew, 1908-; Gilbert, Anthony, 1899-1973.; Gilbert, Michael Francis, 1912-2006.; Golding, Louis, 1895-1958.; Gollancz, Victor, 1893-1967.; Gulik, Robert Hans van, 1910-1967.; Halliday, Brett.; Halsband, Robert, 1914-; Hammett, Dashiell, 1894-1961.; Hare, Cyril, 1900-; Harrington, Joyce.; Harte, Bret, 1836-1902.; Haycraft, Howard, 1905-1991.; Hecht, Ben, 1893-1964.; Heidenfeld, Wolfgang.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961.; Henry, O., 1862-1910.; Herodotus.; Highsmith, Patricia, 1921-1995.; Hilton, James, 1900-1954.; Hoch, Edward D., 1930-2008.; Hughes, Dorothy B. (Dorothy Belle), 1904-1993.; Hughes, Riley.; Hunter, Evan, 1926-2005.; Huston, John, 1906-1987.; Stewart, J. I. M. (John Innes Mackintosh), 1906-1994.; Irish, William, 1903-1968.; Irvine, R. R. (Robert R.); James, P. D.; Jepson, Selwyn, 1899-1989.; Jesse, F. Tennyson (Fryniwyd Tennyson), 1888-1958.; Kantor, MacKinlay, 1904-1977.; Keating, H. R. F. (Henry Reymond Fitzwalter), 1926-; Kelland, Clarence Budington, 1881-1964.; Kemelman, Harry.; Kersh, Gerald, 1911-1968.; King, Stephen, 1947-; Lacy, Ed.; La Farge, Oliver, 1901-1963.; Lardner, Ring, 1885-1933.; Lathen, Emma.; Lawrence, Hilda.; Le Carré, John, 1931-; Lee, Manfred B. (Manfred Bennington), 1905-1971.; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992.; Ley, Willy, 1906-1969.; Lockridge, Frances Louise Davis.; Lockridge, Richard, 1898-1982.; Lofts, Norah, 1904-1983.; Lovesey, Peter.; McBain, Ed, 1926-2005.; McCloy, Helen.; MacDonald, John D. (John Dann), 1916-1986.; MacDonald, Ross.; McGerr, Patricia.; McKelway, St. Clair, 1905-1980.; Mailer, Norman.; Marsh, Ngaio, 1895-1982.; Mather, Berkely.; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965.; Millar, Kenneth, 1915-1983.; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950.; Milne, A. A. (Alan Alexander), 1882-1956.; Montgomery, Bruce, 1921-1978.; Moravia, Alberto, 1907-1990.; Morland, Nigel, 1905-1986.; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957.; Moyes, Patricia.; Narcejac, Thomas, 1908-1998.; Nevins, Francis M.; Niven, David, 1910-1983.; Oboler, Arch, 1907-1987.; Palmer, Stuart, 1905-1968.; Patrick, Q.; Paul, Elliot, 1891-1958.; Pentecost, Hugh, 1903-; Perelman, S. J. (Sidney Joseph), 1904-1979.; Perowne, Barry.; Plumb, J. H. (John Harold), 1911-2001.; Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849.; Pollock, Channing, 1880-1946.; Powell, James.; Powell, Talmage.; Priestley, J. B. (John Boynton), 1894-1984.; Prince, Jerome, 1907-; Prince, Harold, 1928-; Pronzini, Bill.; Quick, Dorothy Alita Kewley, 1907-; Rafferty, S. S.; Rascoe, Burton, 1892-1957.; Rawson, Clayton, 1906-1971.; Redman, Ben Ray, 1896-1961.; Rendell, Ruth, 1930-; Rinehart, Mary Roberts, 1876-1958.; Ritchie, Jack, 1922-1983.; Roberts, S. C. (Sydney Castle), 1887-1966.; Robinson, Jackie, 1919-1972.; Rockwell, Norman, 1894-1978.; Rohmer, Sax, 1883-1959.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Rosten, Leo Calvin, 1908-1997.; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980.; Savage, Ernest, 1918-; Sayers, Dorothy L. (Dorothy Leigh), 1893-1957.; Seeley, Mabel, 1903-1991.; Serling, Rod, 1924-1975.; Shellabarger, Samuel, 1888-1954.; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955.; Shiel, M. P. (Matthew Phipps), 1865-1947.; Simenon, Georges, 1903-1989.; Slesar, Henry.; Spark, Muriel.; Starrett, Vincent, 1886-1974.; Steel, Kurt, 1904-1946.; Steele, Frederic Dorr, 1873-1944.; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968.; Stout, Rex, 1886-1975.; Stribling, T. S. (Thomas Sigismund), 1881-1965.; Strong, L. A. G. (Leonard Alfred George), 1896-1958.; Sturgeon, Theodore.; Symons, Julian, 1912-; Targ, William, 1907-; Tey, Josephine, 1896 or 7-1952.; Thurber, James, 1894-1961.; Treat, Lawrence, 1903-; Twohy, John Roger.; Tyre, Nedra.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Updike, John.; Upfield, Arthur William, 1888-1964.; Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Vickers, Roy.; Watson, Colin.; Waugh, Hillary.; Welles, Orson, 1915-1985.; Westlake, Donald E.; Wilde, Percival, 1887-1953.; Wodehouse, P. G. (Pelham Grenville), 1881-1975.; Woolrich, Cornell, 1903-1968.; Wylie, Philip, 1902-1971.; Yaffe, James, 1927-; Yeats, W. B. (William Butler), 1865-1939.; Detective and mystery stories.; Crime--Fiction.; Novelists, American--20th century.; Contracts.; Awards.; Drafts (literary).; Fiction.; Manuscripts (literary).; Outlines.; Photographs.; Plaques.; Authors.; Critics.; Editors.; Novelists.; Ellery Queen's mystery magazine.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
Papers Dannay, Richard and Douglas Gift
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letter; manuscript of "The Glass Village" and "Notes on Wrightsville" are on microfilm.
Gift of Richard and Douglas Dannay, 1985 & 1987.
- Series I: Cataloged Series
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence
    For complete entries see volume 1 of the Catalog
    - Alexander, David (Box 1)
    - Allingham, Margery
    - Ambler, Eric
    - Anderson, Fred I.
    - Armstrong, Charlotte
    - Arnott, Noeline
    - Arthur, Mildred
    - Arthur, Robert
    - Ashbaugh, Richard
    - Asimov, Isaac
    - Atkey, Bertram
    - Austin, Margaret
    - Avallone, Michael
    - Bachrach, Sylvia Farnham
    - Bailey, H.C.
    - Baldwin, Faith
    - Ball, John
    - Barker, Shirley
    - Barr, Stephen
    - Barzun, Jacques
    - Baxt, George
    - Beach, Stewart
    - Bell, Josephine
    - Bellamy, Ralph
    - Bennett, Margot
    - Bentley, E.C.
    - Bentley, Phyllis
    - Biggle, Lloyd, Jr.
    - Bingham, John Michael Ward, 7th Baron Clanmorris
    - Blochman, Lawrence
    - Block, Lawrence
    - Boileau, Pierre
    - Bond, Raleigh
    - Boucher, Anthony
    - Bradbury, Ray
    - Brand, Christianna
    - Brande, Anna Janet
    - Brandner, Gary P.
    - Brean, Henry
    - Breen, Jon L.
    - Breit, Harvey
    - Bretnor, Reginald
    - Brittain, William
    - Brough, James C.
    - Brown, Frederic
    - Brown, Wenzell
    - Buck, Pearl S.
    - Burgess, Gelett
    - Burnett, W.R.
    - Burroughs, Edgar Rice
    - Bush, Geoffrey
    - Butler, Gwendoline
    - Cain, James M. (Box 2)
    - Caldwell, Taylor
    - Cameron, Owen
    - Campbell, Oscar J.
    - Canby, Henry Seidel
    - Carr, Albert Z.
    - Carr, John Dickson
    - Caspary, Vera
    - Cave, Hugh
    - Cerf, Bennett
    - Chandler, Raymond
    - Charteris, Leslie
    - Child, Charles B.
    - Christ, Jay Finley
    - Christie, Agatha
    - Ciardi, John
    - Clemens, Cyril
    - Coe, Charles Francis
    - Cohen, Roy Octavus
    - Coles, Manning
    - Cornier, Vincent
    - Costain, T.B.
    - Crane, Frances
    - Creasey, John
    - Crispin, Edmund
    - Crofts, Freeman W.
    - Cronin, A.J.
    - Curtis, Richard
    - Curtiss, Ursula
    - Cushing, Richard Cardinal
    - Daly, Elizabeth
    - Daly, Carroll John
    - Daniels, Harold R.
    - Daniels, Norman
    - Dannay, Frederic
    - Davidson, Avram (Box 3)
    - Davis, Dorothy Salisbury
    - Day-Lewis, Cecil
    - Deal, Borden
    - Dedger, David
    - deFord, Miriam Allen
    - de la Torre, Lillian
    - Detzer, Karl
    - Dewey, Thomas E.
    - Dunsany, Edward John Moreton Drax Plunkett, 18th Baron
    - Eberhart, Mignon S.
    - Eckels, Robert E.
    - Ellin, Stanley
    - Elston, Ralph Vaughn
    - Erskine, Laurie York
    - Fairman, Paul
    - Ferrars, Elizabeth
    - Fish, Robert L.
    - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield
    - Fleming, Joan
    - Francis, Dick
    - Freeling, Nicholas
    - Freeman, C.J.A.
    - Fremlin, Celia
    - Gardner, Erle Stanley
    - Garfield, Brian
    - Garve, Andrew
    - Gilbert, Anthony
    - Gilbert, Elliot L.
    - Gilbert, Michael
    - Godfrey, Peter
    - Golding, Louis
    - Gollancz, Livia
    - Gollancz, Victor
    - Gordon, Arthur
    - Gordon, Richard M.
    - Gores, Joe
    - Goulart, Ron
    - Grant, Richard
    - Green, Charles
    - Greene, L. Patrick
    - Gruber, Frank
    - Gulik, Robert H. van
    - Haggard, Edith (Box 4)
    - Hale, Christopher
    - Halliday, Brett
    - Hammett, Dashiell
    - Harrington, Joyce
    - Harrison, Michael
    - Harvester, Simon
    - Hay, Jacob
    - Haycraft, Howard
    - Hayes, Brian
    - Hecht, Ben
    - Hellman, Lillian
    - Helu, Antonio
    - Highsmith, Patricia
    - Hilton, James
    - Hitchens, Dolores
    - Hoch, Edward D.
    - Hoffman, Banesh
    - Holding, James
    - Holding, Elizabeth Sanxay
    - Honce, Charles
    - Howard, John Hayden
    - Hughes, Dorothy B.
    - Hunter, Evan
    - Huston, John
    - Innes, Michael
    - Jesse, F. Tennyson
    - Jordan, Luis A.
    - Kantor, MacKinlay
    - Keating, H.R.F.
    - Kemelman, Harry
    - Kendrick, Baynard
    - Kenneryly, Mitchell
    - Kersh, Gerald
    - Kiernan, John
    - King, Frank
    - King, Rufus
    - Knowlton, Don
    - Kreymborg, Alfred
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood
    - Kummer, Frederic Arnold
    - la Cour, Tage
    - Lacy, Ed
    - Lathen, Emma
    - Lawrence, Hilda
    - Lee, Manfred B. (Box 5)
    - Lerner, Max
    - Lewis, Richard O.
    - Ley, Willy
    - Lipsky, Eleazar
    - Little, Lou
    - Lochte, Richard S.
    - Lockridge, Frances
    - Lovesey, Peter
    - McConnor, Vincent
    - McCulley, Johnston
    - McCutchan, Philip
    - MacDonald, John D.
    - MacDonald, Philip
    - McGerr, Patricia
    - McGivern, William P.
    - McKelway, St. Clair
    - McNear, Robert
    - Martindale, Robert C.
    - Marsh, Ngaio
    - Masur, Harold Q.
    - Mathieson, Theodore
    - Matsumoto, Seicho
    - Maugham, W. Somerset
    - Mayberry, Florence V.
    - Millar, Kenneth
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent
    - Miller, Wade
    - Morland, Nigel
    - Morley, Christopher
    - Morrell, David
    - Narcejac, Thomas
    - Nebel, Frederick
    - Nevins, Francis M., Jr.
    - Nielson, Helen
    - Niven, David
    - Norman, Charles
    - Nolan, William
    - Oboler, Arch
    - Pachter, Josh (Box 6)
    - Palmer, Suart
    - Parry, Henry T.
    - Patrick, Q.
    - Paul, Elliot
    - Peirce, J.F.
    - Perelman, Sidney Joseph
    - Perowne, Barry
    - Peterson, Charles Alden
    - Pierce, John
    - Plumb, Jack
    - Pollock, Channing
    - Porcelain, Lidney E.
    - Porges, Arthur
    - Porter, Joyce
    - Powell, James
    - Prather, Richard S.
    - Priestley, J.B.
    - Priestley, John Boynton
    - Prince, Jerome and Harold
    - Pronzini, Bill
    - Quick, Dorothy
    - Rascoe, Burton
    - Rawson, Clayton
    - Reach, Alice Scanlan
    - Redman, Ben Ray
    - Revesz, Etta
    - Rice, Craig
    - Richter, Joan
    - Rinehart, Mary Roberts
    - Roberts, S.C.
    - Robinson, Jackie
    - Rockwell, Norman
    - Rogers, Joel Townsley
    - Rohmer, Sax
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt
    - Rosten, Leo
    - Roth, Holly
    - Rubin, Rick
    - Rukeyeser, Muriel
    - Rutledge, Nancy
    - Salinger, Pierre
    - Serling, Rod
    - Schier, Norma
    - Seeley, Mabel
    - Shellabarger, Samuel
    - Sherwood, Robert E.
    - Shiel, M.P.
    - Shore, Viola Brothers
    - Simenon, Georges
    - Slater, Elaine
    - Slesar, Henry
    - Speed, Jane
    - Spivak, Lawrence E.
    - Starrett, Vincent
    - Steele, Frederic Don
    - Steele, Wilbur Daniel
    - Stoughton, Arthur A.
    - Stout, Rex
    - Stribling, T.S.
    - Sturgeon, Theodore
    - Suter, John (Box 7)
    - Symons, Julian
    - Targ, William
    - Tey, Josephine
    - Thurber, James
    - Treat, Lawrence
    - Tucker, Luttrell
    - Twohy, Robert
    - Tyre, Nedra
    - Ullman, James M.
    - Untermeyer, Louis
    - Updike, John
    - Upfield, Arthur W.
    - Van de Wetering, Janwillem
    - Van Doren, Carl
    - Van Doren, Irita
    - Van Doren, Mark
    - Vickers, Roy
    - Walsh, Thomas
    - Watson, Colin
    - Waugh, Hilary
    - Weiman, Barbara Owens
    - Weir, Charlene M.
    - Wellen, Edward
    - Westlake, Donald E.
    - White, William
    - Whitehall, Joseph
    - Wilde, Percival
    - Wodehouse, P.G.
    - Woolrich, Cornell
    - Wylie, Philip
    - Wyndham, Martyn
    - Yaffe, James
    - Yates, Donald A.
    - Young, Alan K.
  - Subseries I.2: Manuscripts
    Alphabetical by author. For a complete catalog listing of each individual manuscript see volume 2 of the printed catalog
    - (Box 8-63B.)
    - A To Christie, Agatha "Death.. ." (Box 8)
    - Christie, Agatha "Double.. ." To Dannay, Frederic "The Golden Summer." (Box 9)
    - Dannay, F. "The Golden Summer." (Box 10)
    - Dannay, F. "The Golden Summer." - "A Group of Poems." (Box 11)
    - Dannay, F. "The International Poll to Determine the Ten Best Living Mystery Writers." (Box 12)
    - Dannay, F. "The Macquarries." (Box 13)
    - Dannay, F. "The Macquarries" - "O Lost and Lonely Star." (Box 14)
    - Dannay, F. "O Lost and Lonely Star" - de la Torre, Lillian (Box 15)
    - Dower, Yasuko - Kyne, Peter B. (Box 16)
    - Lambert, Gerard - Perowne, Barry (Box 17)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Adonis.. ." - "The Adventure of the Four." (Box 18)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Adventure of the Needle's" - "The Adventure of the Yang Piece." (Box 20)
    - Queen, Ellery "Af" - "And on the Eighth Day." (Box 21)
    - Queen, Ellery "And on the Eighth Day." (Box 22)
    - Queen, Ellery "And on the Eighth Day" - "Bi" (Box 23)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Black" - "The Body" (Box 24)
    - Queen, Ellery "Br" - "Cam" (Box 25)
    - Queen, Ellery "Camp" - "Cas" (Box 26)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Cat on Many Tails." (Box 27)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Cat of Many Tails." (Box 28)
    - Queen, Ellery "Cop Out." (Box 29)
    - Queen, Ellery "Cri" - "The Crooked Road." (Box 30)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Crooked Road." - "De" (Box 31)
    - Queen, Ellery "Di" - "Do" (Box 32)
    - Queen, Ellery "Dr" - "E" (Box 33)
    - Queen, Ellery "Face to Face." (Box 34)
    - Queen, Ellery "Face to Face" - "Fat" (Box 35)
    - Queen, Ellery "A Fine and Private Place" (Box 36)
    - Queen, Ellery "A Fine and Private Place" - "The Finishing Stroke." (Box 37)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Finishing Stroke." (Box 38)
    - Queen, Ellery "Fir" - "The Fourth Side of the Triangle." (Box 39)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Fourth Side of the Triangle" - "The Glass Village." (Box 40)
    - Queen, Ellery "Gr" - "The House of Brass." (Box 41)
    - Queen, Ellery "The House of Brass" - "Hu" (Box 42)
    - Queen, Ellery "Id" - "Ino" (Box 43)
    - Queen, Ellery "Int" - "Its" (Box 44)
    - Queen, Ellery "J" - "King" (Box 45)
    - Queen, Ellery "King" - "Kr" (Box 46)
    - Queen, Ellery "Kry" - "The Last Woman" (Box 47)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Last Woman" - "Lo" (Box 48)
    - Queen, Ellery "Losers" - "Mu" (Box 49)
    - Queen, Ellery "Mu" - "Ob" (Box 50)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Origin of Evil." (Box 51)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Origin of Evil" - "Ou" (Box 52)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Parisian" - "The Player on the Other Side." (Box 53)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Player on the Other Side" - "The Roman Hat Mystery." (Box 54)
    - Queen, Ellery Sample permission letters - "The Scarlet Letters." (Box 55)
    - Queen, Ellery "The Scarlet Letters" - "A Study in Terror." (Box 56)
    - Queen, Ellery "Stu" - "Ten" (Box 57)
    - Queen, Ellery "Ten Days' Wonder." (Box 58)
    - Queen, Ellery "Ten Days' Wonder" - "The Thin Man's Son." (Box 59)
    - Queen, Ellery "To Vincent Starrett" - "Where Is Bianca?" (Box 60)
    - Queen, Ellery "Whe" - "Who" (Box 61)
    - Queen, Ellery "Who Spies" - "Wr" (Box 62)
    - Queen, Ellery and Lowell Brentano To Queen, Ellery, Jr. (Box 63)
    - Queen, Ellery, Jr. - Si (Box 63A)
    - Queen, Ellery and Lowell Brentano To Queen, Ellery, Jr. (Box 63)
    - Queen, Ellery, Jr. - Si (Box 63A)
    - Sk - Y (Box 63B)
- Series II: Arranged Series
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence
    Arranged by date [Boxes 64-72]
    - 1930s-1939 (Box 64)
    - 1950-1954 (Box 65)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 66)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 67)
    - 1966-1969 (Box 68)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 69)
    - 1974-1977 (Box 70)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 71)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 72)
  - Subseries II.2: Manuscripts
    Boxes 73-78 & Boxes 89-90
    - Introductions to Department of First Stories and anonymous manuscripts. (Box 73)
    - "The Ten Most Famous Fictional Detectives of all Time" -- Hilda Dannay's death: correspondence and funeral registers -- The Queen's Awards: 1947 and 1948..galleys, proofs, etc. (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous notes and signatures collected by Dannay. (Box 90)
    - Photocopies of manuscripts. (Box 74)
    - Photocopies of manuscripts. (Box 75)
    - Fragments of manuscripts. (Box 76)
    - Fragments of manuscripts. (Box 77)
    - Fragments of manuscripts. (Box 78)
- Series III: Documents
  - Subseries III.1: Cataloged and Arranged Documents
    Arranged alphabetically [Boxes 79-81]
    - Dannay, Frederic, 2 Jan. 1965 & April 1977 (Box 79)
    - Dannay & Lee, 15 Sept. 1931 & 23 Nov. 1953
    - Lee & Dannay, 13 Oct. 1943; 6 March 1946; 2 July 1947; 27 Nov. 1967
    - Wells, Orson, 3 Aug. 1970
    - Contracts, A - F.
    - Contracts, J - N. (Box 80)
    - Contracts P - W. (Box 81)
  - Subseries III.2: Arranged Documents
    Arranged chronologically [Boxes 82-87]
    - Documents, 1930-1963 (Box 82)
    - Documents, 1964-1967 (Box 83)
    - Documents, 1968-1972 (Box 84)
    - Documents, 1973-1978 (Box 85)
    - Documents, 1979-1982 (Box 86)
    - Documents: ledger books. (Box 87)
- Series IV: Artwork and Photographs
  Cataloged and arranged
  - Dannay, Frederic Photograph (Box 88)
  - Doyle, Sir Arthur Conan Photograph
  - Fletcher, J. S. Photograph.
  - Lee, Manfred B. Photograph.
  - "S. F." Photograph
    [Cartoons with a mystery theme]
  - Sayers, Dorothy Photograph.
  - "The Ten Best Active Mystery Writers of All Time", (Photograph)
  - Woolrich, Cornell Photograph.
  - Arranged photographs and artwork
- Series V: Printed Materials
  Boxes 91-100
  - Printed stories (Box 91)
  - Printed stories. (Box 92)
  - Printed stories. (Box 93)
  - Magazines and booklets. (Box 94)
  - Magazines and booklets. (Box 95)
  - Magazines and booklets. (Box 96)
  - Magazines and booklets. (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials. (Box 98)
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 99)
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 100)
- Series VI: Objects and Memorabilia
  - (Box 101)
- Series VII: Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
  This part of the collection comprises 87 Boxes of manuscripts submitted to EQMM from its beginning in 1941 till the early 1980s. Each manuscripts has been cataloged. For a complete guide to authors and their manuscripts volumes 2 & 3 of the Catalog
  - Author's manuscripts.
- Series VIII: Arranged manuscripts
  - Breen, Jon L. "The Jury Box", (2 folders) (Box 87)
  - Carr, John Dixon "The Jury Box", (4 folders)
  - Penzler, Otto "Crime Dossier", (6 folders)
  - Porter, R. E. "Crime Beat", (3 folders)
  - Steinbrunner, Chris "Bloody Visions", (2 folders)
  - Miscellaneous, (1 folder)
  - Book reviews, (1 folder)
  - Indices and Table of Contents, (1 folder)
  - Dannay, Frederic Notes, (1 folder)